Ryan Maddumahewa

Australian Permanent Resident

T: 0426189706 E: rbasehewa@gmail.com G: https://github.com/rbasehewa

Career Objective

Having more than two years' experience working with software applications (C# in .NET and React JS). I am a Master's in Information Technology graduate seeking a developer role. I am seeking a challenging position where I can make a valuable contribution to the organisation.

Best Tech skills: REST/ SOAP web services on .NET in C# using Git and Jira.

Personal Attributes

Communication Skills

- Worked closely with internal and external stakeholders
- Able to communicate clearly and effectively with various types of people
- Able to express key information succinctly and professionally

Time management and organisational skills

- Able to work with a group, share ideas, respect other's views, and make good decisions to achieve project goals
- Always ready to accept new challenge
- Dedicated, honest and punctual

Problem-solving skills

- Functional, system integration and UAT experience
- Creating and executing functional, non-functional requirements
- Strong aptitude to solve problems and make decisions under pressure
- Experience technical writing skills of writing test plans, user manuals, system changes and release notes

Key Skills Summary

.NET in C#	PHP	Angular	HTML/HTML5
CSS/SCSS	JavaScript	React Js	GitHub
Java	Linux	Mac OS	Windows
MySQL/MSSQL	Postman	Bitbucket	SVN
TFS	VSCode	NetBeans	MSSQL

Education

Professional Year Program for ICT

Sep 2018 - Aug 2019

Performance Education, Adelaide

This program is recognised by the Australian Computer Society (ACS) and assists graduates to improve their employability by developing additional workplace and business skills.

Master of Information Technology

Charles Sturt University, Sydney

Key learning areas: Java and Python programming, Project management, Object model

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Jan 2011 - Nov 2014

July 2016 - July 2018

Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology (SLIIT)

Key learning areas: Relation database management system, Data structures and algorithms, Distributed computer-based software development

Achievements

Awarded certificate of recognition intern of the month

July 2019

Performance Education, Adelaide

Successfully completed Bank of America project

Dec 2017

First Technology, Singapore

Published and certified a research paper

Feb 2012

"A study for software engineering metrics for ERP development projects" in online journal in IJARET.

Professional Experience

Software Developer (part-time) – I Teach you Learn

May 2019 - Present

I Teach you learn provide a platform for teachers based in Sri Lanka, Australia, and New Zealand to publish their online classes and tech start-up.

Key responsibilities

- Excelled with PHP in Laravel package with Angular 9, HTML5, SCSS, iQuery and Node is
- Experienced in UI design, created documentation of system changes and release notes
- Having experience on go through with new framework documentation and maintain the code quality
- Experienced with working in GitHub and Bitbucket tool
- Analyse test activities and generate reports to support SDLC procedures

Frontend developer (part-time) – Zippycrowd Pty Ltd

Oct 2020 - Feb 2021

ZippyCrowd is a free world-of-mouth platform helping people in small businesses get new customers through personal recommendations.

Key responsibilities

- Experienced on Angular 6, HTML5, SCSS, ¡Query and git server
- Created documentation for user information, sitemaps, functionality and usability
- Ensured all sprints tasks worked with Jira Software
- Experienced with Jira issue tracker and figma design tool
- Having experienced test and deploying high quality web, server side and database level applications

Junior Web Developer - Enee Solutions Pty Ltd

May 2019 - Aug 2019

Enee solutions is a new e-commerce platform and provide best IT hardware and software purchases easier, quicker, and cheaper.

Key responsibilities

- Excelled with PHP in Laravel package, HTML5, SCSS, jQuery and React js
- Utilised Autotask tool to integrate API for Enee's client's data which was open tickets and close tickets based in a fortnightly round-up email report
- Experienced in create and maintain support documentation (Autotask and Jira APIs)
- Experienced with Jira issue tracker and able to fetch the current projects and list of users who are working with current sprints
- Applied best practices to enhance project structure and namespaces
- Worked on responsive web projects and web services (REST/SOAP)
- Communicated with the team regularly and work collaboratively

Junior Software Engineer- Creation Application Pty Ltd

Jan 2014 - Feb 2016

Creation Application is a UK based software development company in Sri Lanka, and owns 100+ projects all over UK, Including government applications and tech start-ups.

Key responsibilities

- Assisted with analysing client requirements using mock-ups with fact-finding techniques
- Developed an internal company WIKI site and developing initiative moke-ups
- Ensured all tasks given by senior programmers were finished within a given time frame
- Integrated Web APIs using .NET n C# and PHP frameworks
- Experienced in working with WordPress ecosystem
- Maintained code quality as per the company's standard
- Having experienced test and deploying high quality web, server side and database level applications
- Worked with the agile project management system

References

Referees provided upon request.